https://www.editors.ca/privacy-policy

Jump to Navigation
You are hereHome > Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Policy purpose
The purpose of this policy is to meet the requirements of the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act.
Policy statement
The Editors' Association of Canada/Association canadienne des réviseurs respects the privacy of its members. It is committed to applying privacy principles to allow members to participate fully in association activities without compromising personal information.
Definitions used within this policy
Personal information, as defined by the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act, means "information about an identifiable individual, but does not include the name, title or business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization."
Applicability
This policy applies to personal information collected by the association and/or its branches and twigs as it conducts business, including providing member services.
Responsibility
The Editors' Association of Canada (Editors Canada) will comply with all relevant provisions of the federal Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act with respect to collecting, using, storing and disposing of personal information.
In particular, Editors Canada will collect personal information only to carry out the aims and objectives of the association as set out in its Bylaw No. 1 (2014).
Editors Canada will advise individuals who voluntarily provide personal information that they are consenting to its collection by the association.
Editors Canada will not use or disclose collected personal information for any purpose other than the aims and objectives of the association.
Those persons in the association who keep and maintain for the association records containing personal information will make reasonable security arrangements against unauthorized access, use, modification, disclosure or disposal of such records.
The executive director serves as the association's privacy officer.
The executive director is responsible for reporting known non-compliance to the national executive council.
The privacy officer will be the association's contact point for any complaints against Editors Canada under the Act.
Any complaints unresolved by the privacy officer will be referred to the national executive council for consideration and appropriate action.
Contact information
Enquiries about this policy should be directed to the national office of the Editors' Association of Canada.
info@editors.ca
www.editors.ca / www.reviseurs.ca
416-975-1379
1-866-226-3348 (toll-free)
Authority
This policy is issued under the authority of the members of the Editors' Association of Canada.
Substantive revisions to this policy must be ratified by a vote of the association's national executive council.
This policy will be reviewed every five years.
References
There are no guidelines for implementing this policy.
Privacy officer:
Natasha Bood
Executive Director
Editors' Association of Canada
Effective date: December 2014; last revised November 2014
Public menu [EN]
AboutAwardsTom Fairley AwardWinners
Award guidelines
Who was Tom Fairley?
BoldFace: The official blog of Editors TorontoVolunteering for BoldFace
QuébecLooking for an Editor?
HireWhy hire an editor?
What can a professional editor do for you?
FeesHow do we compare?
Conference Events (reception, etc.)
